<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TUTORIALS>
        <SECTION TITLE="How to download..." TYPE="0">
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Password-protected sites" DESCRIPTION="How to specify a username and password in the Project Properties or enter them into the URL">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Downloading password-protected Web sites.</h3>
<p>
        There are two kinds of password-protected Web sites. One type asks for a username
        and password in a standard Windows-type dialog (BASIC and NTLM authentication,)
        while the other type requires you to logon directly on a Web page.</p>
<h4>
        Web sites that require BASIC and NTLM-authentication.</h4>
<p>
        To download this type of site, either specify the username and password in the <span
                class="code">Project Properties dialog | Advanced | Password section</span>,
        or type them directly in the URL, such as: <span class="code">http://username:password@www.server.com/...</span></p>
<p>
        Notice that a colon separates the password from the username and the <span class="code">
                @</span> symbol separates them from the server name.</p>
<p>
        Some sites use NTLM authentication, which looks like the above, but with a third
        box labeled "DOMAIN" along with the username and password. Enter the domain name
        along with the username in the same field in the <span class="code">Project Properties
                dialog | Passwords</span> this way:</p>
<p>
        <span class="code">DOMAIN\username</span></p>
<p>
        The backslash symbol separates the domain name from the username. When you are done
        with the Project Properties changes, click the OK button to save them.</p>
<p class="note">
        NTLM authentication is supported only in the Pro and Enterprise editions of Offline
        Explorer.</p>
<h4>
        Authentication in a Web form.</h4>
<p>
        It is easy to download this type of site.</p>
<p>
        You need to browse to the logon page of the site using the internal Browser of %OENAME%.</p>
<p>
        If you need to download the site immediately and only once, you can proceed with
        the logon and begin downloading the desired pages using %OENAME%. The program will
        use the session cookies of the logged on site from the internal browser.</p>
<p>
        You can also record the logon form contents in a Project, so that %OENAME% will
        know how to log itself on whenever you wish to download the site. This is useful
        when you want to schedule the site download or perform it later, or if you want
        to update the downloaded site in the future.</p>
<p>
        Once you have entered your username and password on the logon page in the internal
        browser, press and hold the <span class="code">Alt + Ctrl</span> keys on your keyboard, click the Logon
        (or Submit) button in the Web form and release the keyboard buttons. You should
        get a new Project that contains the Web form information recorded in the URL field.</p>
<p>
        Adjust the Project settings as you wish (set the Level and other parameters) and
        click the OK button to save the Project. You may begin downloading at any time.</p>
<p>
        It is also recommended to make sure that the "Use alternate connection method" box
        is checked in the Internet tab of the Ribbon.</p>
<p class="note">
        The form recording method is supported only in the Pro and Enterprise editions of
        Offline Explorer.</p>
]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Streaming Audio or Video" DESCRIPTION="You can download a RealPlayer or MS Media Player streaming file to your hard disk for later viewing">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Downloading Video and Audio streams to your hard disk.</h3>
<p>
        Without %OENAME%, you can only play MS Media Player and Real Player clips online.
        You cannot save them for later viewing and must stream it from the Internet again
        if you wish to view it again.</p>
<p>
        Also, if you have a slow or unreliable Internet connection, watching video clips
        online involves low quality or unstable sound and picture.</p>
<p>
        Overcome these limitations!</p>
<p>
        Offline Explorer Pro and Enterprise editions overcomes these problems by downloading
        the desired streams to your hard disk so you can play them as often as you like,
        even without any Internet connection.</p>
<p>
        Since video files may disappear from Web sites or be replaced with other files,
        downloading them will help you to build your own media library.</p>
<p>
        It is even possible to load the highest-quality videos on any kind of connection,
        including via modem. Of course, this will take more time than on a high-speed DSL,
        but the video quality will be preserved and you will enjoy it without distortions.</p>
<p>
        All this is possible because Offline Explorer Pro and Enterprise support streaming
        protocols - RTSP (for RealPlayer streams) and MMS (for MS Media Player streams.)</p>
<h4>
        How to download media streams.</h4>
<p>
        You can add a link to %OENAME% that begins with the <span class="code">rtsp://</span>
        or <span class="code">mms://</span> prefix and download it.</p>
<p>
        You can also have %OENAME% download a Web page with links to media files and the
        program will load the desired streams automatically.</p>
<p>
        It is recommended that you set the Level setting to 1 or more depending on the Web
        site layout, and change the <span class="code">Location boxes</span> of the <span
                class="code">Project Properties | File Filters | Audio and Video</span> sections
        to "Load from any site." This is necessary because often streaming media files are
        located on other Web sites.</p>
<p>
        Do not forget to click <span class="code">OK</span> button to save changes when
        you finish editing Project Properties.</p>
<h4>
        Selecting the desired stream bandwidth.</h4>
<p>
        Some audio and video streams may contain several versions of different quality in
        the same URL.</p>
<p>
        You can select which version you want to download using the <span class="code">Maximum
                RTSP bandwidth</span> setting in the <span class="code">Options dialog | Speed section</span>.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Web Form submission results" DESCRIPTION="Loading search engine sites, quiz results, etc.">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Recording Web form contents and downloading submission results.</h3>
<p>
        There are various Web forms used on the Internet. Some of them help you to search
        Web sites, some are for logon protected site areas and others perform navigation
        or answer questions.</p>
<p>
        Offline Explorer Pro and Enterprise editions can record any Web form parameters
        and save them as a Project.</p>
<p>
        Browse to the page with the desired Web form in %OENAME% internal browser, fill
        in the form fields, then press and hold down <span class="code">Alt + Ctrl</span>
        keys on your keyboard, click the Submit button in the Web form and release the keyboard
        buttons. You will see a new Project that contains the Web form information recorded
        in the URL field.</p>
<p>
        Adust the Project settings as you wish (set <span class="code">Level</span>, other
        parameters) and click the <span class="code">OK</span> button to save the Project.
        You can start downloading at any time.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="A missing link when browsing downloaded Web site" DESCRIPTION="If you see that a page was not downloaded because of the Project Level or other restrictions, it is easy to add the missing page to the Project and load it immediately">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Loading missing links when browsing a Project offline.</h3>
<p>
        When you finish downloading a Project and you start browsing offline, you may find
        that not all links were downloaded.</p>
<p>
        In this case, %OENAME% displays a page with a message that the page cannot be found
        offline. You may notice two links on the page. One follows the online location of
        the missing page.</p>
<p>
        You can drag the online link into the Project in the Projects tree. Drop the link
        on the Project you are browsing and %OENAME% will offer to create a new Project
        or to add the link to the existing Project. Select the second option and the link
        will be downloaded immediately.</p>
<p>
        You can refresh the page you are browsing and the missing page will be available
        offline.</p>
<p>
        The page with the missing page message also contains another link. If you click
        the link, it will do exactly the same as dragging an online link to the Project.
        However sometimes the second link is not visible because of narrow frames, etc.</p>
<p class="note">
        Downloading missing links is supported only in the Pro and Enterprise editions of
        Offline Explorer.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Mirror sites" DESCRIPTION="Preventing duplicates when mirror sites are cross linked">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        How to prevent duplicated files on your hard disk when mirror sites are cross linked.</h3>
<p>
        Frequently www.server.com contains absolutely the same information as server.com.</p>
<p>
        If both sites contain links to each other, you will end with two copies of the same
        site on you hard disk.</p>
<p>
        Offline Explorer Pro and Enterprise editions have a new <span class="code">URL Substitutes</span>
        feature that can greatly help here. You can find it in the <span class="code">Project
                Properties dialog | Advanced</span> section.</p>
<p>
        You will need to add a rule to convert one type of link to another. For example,
        if you are downloading from <span class="code">http://www.server.com</span>, then
        all links to <span class="code">http://server.com</span> have to be replaced with
        links to the first server.</p>
<p>
        This rule is simple (type it in the corresponding fields of the URL Substitutes
        dialog):</p>
<p>
        In all URLs <span class="code">http://server.com/*</span> replace <span class="code">
                http://server.com/</span> with <span class="code">http://www.server.com/</span>.</p>
<p>
        Click the <span class="code">Add</span> button below and the <span class="code">OK</span>
        button to save the rule. Click another <span class="code">OK</span> button to save
        changes in the <span class="code">Project settings</span>.</p>
<p>
        Now all links to the mirror site will lead to the starting server automatically.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Removing unwanted links from the Queue" DESCRIPTION="How to stop downloading links from the Queue using keywords">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        How to stop downloading links from the Queue using keywords.</h3>
<p>
        You may notice %OENAME% starting to download links that you don't need. For example,
        you may not need the printer-friendly version of an article. There is an easy way
        to abort downloading of these links.</p>
<p>
        First, press the <span class="code">F9</span> key to suspend the download.</p>
<p>
        Second, go to the <span class="code">Queue</span> tab, right-click on any URL in
        the Queue and then click the <span class="code">Select by Mask...</span>. Type the
        keyword you want to use to select files and click the OK button.</p>
<p>
        The keyword can be simple, such as:</p>
<p>
        <span class="code">?printversion=true</span><br />
        or<br />
        <span class="code">http://*.adserver.*/*</span></p>
<p>
        %OENAME% will select all URLs in the Queue that match the keyword. This may take
        some time if there are thousands of URLs in the Queue.</p>
<p>
        Third, right-click any of the selected links (to preserve the selection) and choose
        <span class="code">Abort</span>.</p>
<p>
        Fourth, go to the <span class="code">Projects</span> tab, select the <span class="code">
                Project</span> you are downloading and change its <span class="code">Properties</span>
        to prevent downloading the links you don't want.</p>
<p>
        Now you can press <span class="code">F9</span> again to resume downloading.</p>
<p>
        You can also use the above to keep the desired URLs and remove all others - just
        use the <span class="code">Invert Selection</span> feature before aborting them.</p>
<p class="note">
        The Queue Manager feature is accessible only in the Pro and Enterprise editions
        of Offline Explorer.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
        </SECTION>
        <SECTION TITLE="Converting downloaded sites" TYPE="0">
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Placing downloaded Web site on a USB key" DESCRIPTION="Copy downloaded site files on a mobile device to browse it on other computers">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Browsing downloaded Web site on any computer from a mobile memory device.</h3>
<p>
        You can make a Web site viewable offline without any additional software. All you
        need is a browser (MS Internet Explorer, Netscape, Opera, etc.)</p>
<p>
        When you finish downloading a site to your hard disk, please select the corresponding
        <span class="code">Project</span>, go to <span class="code">File | Export</span>
        in the main menu and export the site to the disk that corresponds to your USB drive
        (For example, disk G:\ .)</p>
<p>
        Please make sure you check the <span class="code">"Use Standard extensions for files
                with known file types"</span> box before you start exporting. You can also check
        the <span class="code">"Make AutoRun CD"</span> box. If the system supports autorun
        on the USB drive, the site will be automatically opened when you insert the drive.</p>
<p>
        If autorun does not work on the USB drive, you can open the contents.htm file on
        the USB drive to start browsing the site. On most systems it is enough to double-click
        contents.htm in Windows Explorer when you view the USB drive contents.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Burning a site to a CD disk" DESCRIPTION="Easy steps to prepare downloaded sites for CD burning">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Burning a Web site to a CD or DVD disc.</h3>
<p>
        %OENAME% doesn't contain CD writing code itself, but it can prepare a downloaded
        Web site (Project) for easy CD burning.</p>
<p>
        Most Web sites use very long filenames that are not compatible with the filesystem
        used on CDs. That's why it is necessary to export a Web site to a CD-compatible
        format. Export copies to the selected directory of only files that belong to the
        Project.</p>
<p>
        Please select the desired Project and select <span class="code">File | Export</span>
        from the main menu. This will copy the loaded site to some directory which should
        be later burned to a CD-R or CD-RW disk. In the Export dialog you should select
        <span class="code">Joliet - CD-R 64 symbols</span> in the Filenames format field
        and check the <span class="code">Use standard extensions for files with known file types</span>
        box.</p>
<p>
        You can also make an <span class="code">AutoRun CD</span>, which will be automatically
        browsed when you insert the disk. Make sure that the <span class="code">"Create contents
                file"</span> is checked for easier browsing from the CD.</p>
<p>
        Now click the <span class="code">Export</span> button and wait until the process
        completes. Then write the exported directory contents using your favorite CD burning
        program.</p>
<p>
        You should calculate the Project files size before exporting it by using the Size
        button in the <span class="code">Export dialog</span> next to the <span class="code">
                Browse</span> button.</p>
<p>
        Most CD-R/RW discs can contain not more than 650 or 700 megabytes of information.
        Some CD recorders can support larger volumes, but you need to consult your CD recorder
        manual.</p>
<p>
        If a Web site's file size is over the available CD disc volume, you can export it
        to an <span class="code">HTML Help</span> (CHM) file. CHM files compress Web pages,
        so the same Web site occupies much less space than when using other formats. Thus,
        a typical CD disc can include over one gigabyte of a compressed Web site.</p>
<p>
        You can choose HTML Help format in the <span class="code">Put files to</span> field
        of the Export dialog.</p>
<p>
        HTML Help files can be browsed on Windows 98/ME/2000/XP and newer systems.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Transferring a downloaded Project to another computer" DESCRIPTION="Make a compressed Project backup to restore the Project in another copy of the program.">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        %OENAME% can create compressed Project backup files.</h3>
<p>
        Select the desired Project and go to the <span class="code">Tools | Backup/Restore</span> menu. Select
        <span class="code">Backup Projects</span>.</p>
<p>
        You will be prompted to type a filename to which to save the Project. All Project
        backup files have the .boe extension.</p>
<p>
        Backup files contain Project settings, its Map and all downloaded Web sites that
        belong to the Project.</p>
<p>
        You can restore the Project either by double-clicking the .boe file or by selecting
        it using the <span class="code">Tools | Backup/Restore | Restore Projects</span> menu.</p>
<p>
        Backup files are also useful if you want to transfer the Project to another computer.</p>
<p>
        You can backup several Projects or Project Folders at once the same way. Just select
        the Projects using <span class="code">Shift-click</span> or <span class="code">Ctrl-click</span> before backing them up.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Sending Project settings to a friend" DESCRIPTION="Share your Project settings without downloaded files with others">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Share your Project settings without downloaded files with others.</h3>
<p>
        If you want to save Project settings in a file, select the desired Project and click
        the Copy button. Now run Notepad and paste the Project there. Save it to a text
        file.</p>
<p>
        Now you can send the text file by E-mail or transfer it to another computer.</p>
<p>
        To insert the Project into another copy of %OENAME%, open the text file in Notepad,
        select the whole text and copy it to the clipboard. Then switch to %OENAME% and
        click the Paste button. The Project will be added to the currently selected folder.</p>
<p>
        You can transfer several Projects or Project Folders at once the same way. Just
        select the Projects using <span class="code">Shift-click</span> or <span class="code">
                Ctrl-click</span> before copying them to clipboard.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
        </SECTION>
        <SECTION TITLE="Adding Projects" TYPE="0">
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="How to insert a number of URLs from a text or other file" DESCRIPTION="Using clipboard for easy Projects creation">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Adding several URLs to %OENAME%.</h3>
<p>
        Adding a set of URLs can be done in few mouse clicks.</p>
<p>
        If you have them in a text file (one URL per line,) open the file in Notepad or
        in any other text editor, select all the text and copy it to the clipboard. Now
        switch to %OENAME% and click the Paste button on the toolbar.</p>
<p>
        Offline Explorer (standard) can have only one URL per Project, so the program creates
        a number of new Projects - one per URL inserted.</p>
<p>
        Offline Explorer Pro and Enterprise editions create one Project with all pasted
        URLs in it. If you need to create multiple Projects, please hold down the <span class="code">
                Shift</span> key while clicking the Paste button.</p>
<p>
        If you want to alter settings in the newly-created Projects, create a new Template
        <span class="code">File | Templates menu</span> with the desired settings before
        pasting the URLs. You can choose the Template to apply to new Projects using the
        drop-down menu on the right side of the Paste button.</p>
<p>
        Copying URLs from an MS Excel file is also easy. If all URLs are on the same column,
        select cells with links on the row and click the Copy button on the MS Excel toolbar.
        Then paste them to %OENAME% the same way as above.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
        </SECTION>
        <SECTION TITLE="Solving Problems" TYPE="1">
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="What to do if you loose your Projects" DESCRIPTION="Restoring Projects file from backup copies">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        What to do if you lose your Projects</h3>
<p>
        In most cases, it is easy to recover lost projects. All Projects are in the webdown.dat
        file, and there are many backups of that file.</p>
<p>
        Open the <span class="code">Options dialog | Advanced | File Locations</span> section.
        Please see the Projects, Maps and Templates folder location.</p>
<p>
        Now quit %OENAME%, open Windows Explorer and browse to that folder. Select all files
        with the <b>webdown</b> filename (webdown.dat is the Projects file, the rest are
        backup copies) and copy them to another directory to keep them intact.</p>
<p>
        Select the most recent file with the maximum size and copy it back under the webdown.dat
        filename.</p>
<p>
        Start %OENAME% to see if all of your Projects are in place. If something is wrong
        with the Projects list, try to repeat the process with another webdown file.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
        </SECTION>
        <SECTION TITLE="Converting downloaded sites" TYPE="1">
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="How to browse an exported site from a CD under MacOS" DESCRIPTION="Setting up System 9 and earlier to support Joliet filesystem">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Tuning up MacOS to browse downloaded sites from CDs</h3>
<p>
        The Joliet CD filesystem format is not natively supported under MacOS System 9 and
        earlier.</p>
<p>
        Starting with MacOS System X you can seamlessly use CDs burned on other computer
        systems, such as Windows and Linux.</p>
<p>
        To enhance System 9 you need to download a system extension to work with Joliet-compatible
        CDs. The extension is available here:</p>
<p>
        <a href="http://www.tempel.org/joliet/index.html" target="_blank">http://www.tempel.org/joliet/index.html</a></p>
<p>
        After this extension is installed everything works the same way as on Windows systems.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
        </SECTION>
        <SECTION TITLE="Downloading" TYPE="1">
                <TUTORIAL TITLE="Why URL Filters may stop working?" DESCRIPTION="Changing File Filters | Location box setting overrides URL Filters restrictions">
                        <![CDATA[
<h3>
        Why URL Filters may stop working?</h3>
<p>
        The most common reason why URL Filters do not work as expected is an incorrect Location
        setting. All <span class="code">Project Properties dialog | File Filters</span>
        categories have a Location box which allows you to overwrite URL Filters restrictions
        for the given category of files with other settings.</p>
<p>
        For example, if the Project URL Filters have <span class="code">Load only from the starting
                server</span> selected, you can still allow <span class="code">File Filters | Images</span>
        to be loaded from any site by selecting that in its Location box.</p>
<p>
        Although this brings flexibility to fine-tuning your Project, it can cause confusion.</p>
<p>
        Please go through all File Filters categories in the Project Properties dialog to
        see if all of them contain <span class="code">Load using URL Filters settings</span>
        in their Location boxes. This setting is recommended to prevent loading from all
        sites.</p>
                        ]]>
                </TUTORIAL>
        </SECTION>
</TUTORIALS>
